Guide to the New York City Labor Chorus Records WAG.361
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City Labor Chorus Records
1987-2020
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York City Labor Chorus
Vogel, Jeffrey
WAG.361
4.25 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript boxes, and 2 oversize folders.
1.37 Gigabytes
5 sound discs (cd)
The New York City Labor Chorus, with 75 members representing over 20 local unions and District Councils, was founded in 1991. Its music focuses on the message of workers' history and their struggles for social and economic justice. This collection consists of the performance group's administrative records, and includes meeting agendas, meeting minutes, correspondence, sheet music, ephemera and publications, performance programs, and press releases that document tours, performances, scheduling and other planning, membership, publicity, meetings and rehearsals, and organizational structure. The collection also includes commercial recordings of the group's performances.
Scope and Contents
The New York City Labor Chorus Records (dated 1987-2020) consists of the performance group's administrative records, and includes meeting agendas, meeting minutes, correspondence, sheet music, ephemera and publications, performance programs, and press releases that document tours, performances, scheduling and other planning, membership, publicity, meetings and rehearsals, and organizational structure. The collection also includes commercial recordings of the group's performances.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged into two series, maintaining the order in which they were received from the donor.
Series I. Original Donation
Series II. 2021 Accretion
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jeffrey Vogel, July 2018, with an accretion donated in November 2021. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2019.003 and 2021.072.
Historical Note
The New York City Labor Chorus, with 75 members representing over 20 local unions and District Councils, was founded in 1991. Its music focuses on the message of workers' history and their struggles for social and economic justice.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual material has not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Material not yet digitized will need to have an access copy made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Choral music.; Labor unions; Concerts.; Anniversaries; Performances.; Posters.; Vogel, Jeffrey; Fairweather, Geoffrey
- Series I. Original Donation, 2000-2018; .25 linear feet in 1 half manuscript box and 2 oversize folders
  - Event Programs, 2011-2018 (Box 1)
  - Soul of the City Materials, undated (Box 1)
  - Poster, circa 2000 (Box Shared Tamiment 048, Folder 3)
  - Benefit Concert Poster, 2018 (Box Shared Tamiment 050, Folder 9, Box Shared Special Collections 001)
- Series II. 2021 Accretion, 1987-2020; 3.25 linear feet in 5 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box; 5 sound discs (cd)
  - Board Agendas and Meeting Notes, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board Agendas, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Applications, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Attendance Forms, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Active Chorus Members, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Artwork, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Anthony, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chorus Applications -- Blank, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Attendance Letter, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ads in Magazines, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Adler, Cy, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bookings Form, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Booking Sheet, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bank Deposit Forms -- Blank, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NYC Labor Chorus Board (Original), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - NYC Labor Chorus Proposal and Bylaws (Original), 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bylaws, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bread and Roses, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bernhardt, Debra, circa 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Button Order -- Fighting for the Arts, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Members, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CD and Tape Purchase -- On the March, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cocktail, CD, and Holiday Party, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Chemical Bank Account, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Concert Program, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Channel 13 WNET Video Proposal, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with Chorus Members, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Dance, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
  - Dress Code Suggestion, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Ruby Dee and Ossie Davis, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Dumakude, Thuli, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Duncan, Dorothy, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Democratic Inauguration, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Democratic Convention, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Board Member Election Results, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Employer Letter, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1199, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Labor Chorus Proposal -- Funding, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Fundraising Meeting, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hunt Alternatives Fund, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Foundations for Possible Grants -- NY Fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Human Rights CANTATA, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Humphries, Pat, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Outfits and Jackets, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Jacobs, Don, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Labor Heritage Foundation Catalogue, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Labor Heritage Foundation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Leventhal, Harold, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Local 802, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Membership List, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Members -- Original, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - McRae, Percy, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Music Table of Contents, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sheet Music for Chorus, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Music -- Human Rights Cantata, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Glenn Maurer Graphics -- Tape Art, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Music Subcommittee, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Chorus Members by Local, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, Meeting Notes, Mailing Announcements, 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter to Chorus Members, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - New Repertoire Ideas, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - NOLA Studios, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New Applicants Letter, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chorus Order Form -- Poster, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Oasis Recording -- Tape Production, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Oasis Contract -- CDs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Programs from Performance Events, 1991-2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Peterson, David (State Senator), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Press, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Proclamation, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Phone List, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Performances, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Performance Notes, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Programs from Performances, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Performance Invoices, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 1993-2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Phone Numbers, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C. Performance, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Prompt Printing Press, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Patron Form, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Repertoire, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chorus Repertoire, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rivera, Dennis, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Paul Robeson Tribute (Carnegie Hall), undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Rabinowitz, Bobbie, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Labor Chorus Reception, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Ransome, Dan, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Repertoires for Various Performances, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Recording Agreement, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Room List for Washington, D.C. Trip, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Labor Choir Resume, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Rules and Reguations for Chorus Members, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Seeger Concert Birthday Proposal, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Seeger Concert Music, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Schedule -- Rehearsals, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - South Africa, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Sweden Trip -- Income/Expenses, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Sweden Tour, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Symphony Space Rental Agreement, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Sing Out! Review, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Small Group Choir, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Survey of Chorus Form, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Schedules, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Speech on Chorus Beginning at Labor Arts Exchange, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Sign Language Interpreter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Tape Notes Regarding Chorus Concert, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Tenth Anniversary, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - T-shirt Order, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - T-shirt Re-order, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Unions in Chorus, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Unions to Contact, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Unions Requesting Information, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Shortlist of Unions in Chorus, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Member Listings by Voice, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Uniform, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Foundations Report by Voytek, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Charles Lawrence Keith and Clara Miller Foundation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Musical Integrity Ideas, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Public Relations Sheet, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brochures -- Other Choruses, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Promotional Piece, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - UIB Information, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Labor 2000 Festival (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Labor Publications, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notices and Programs, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Notices, Programs, and Ephemera, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 20-23)
  - Notices, Programs, and Ephemera, 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ads Sent to Printer, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Concert, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ads and Tickets, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Benefit Concert, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chorus Inquiries, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Concert Income/Expenses Tally Sheets, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notes, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Committee Sign-Up Sheet for Benefit Performance, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1994 Concerts (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Concert 1995 -- Cost List (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Concert 1995 -- Cooper Union Agreement (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Concert 1995 -- Script for MC (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Concert 1995 -- Mayoral Regrets (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Concert 1995 -- Program (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Concert 1995 -- Flyer (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Concert 1995 -- Tickets (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Concert 1995 -- HIP Request for Reception (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Concert 1995 -- Press Release (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Concert 1995 -- Income (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Concert 1995 -- Expenses (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Concert 1995 -- Collegium Sound Contract (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Concert 1995 -- Ads (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Labor Chorus Ads, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Journal Communications, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Journal Ads, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Labor Chorus Budget, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Script (Concert), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - HIP Donation Memo, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Benefit Program Journal, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Journal Returns, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bulk Ticket Orders, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Tickets, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Journal, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Performance, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Leaflet, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Program, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Raffle Committee, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Press, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Publicity Committee, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Committee Sign-ups, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Leaflet Regarding Concert, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Concert Checklist, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Concert Donations, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Raffle, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Labor Chorus Benefit -- Appeal to Inactive Members, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fasanella, Ralph -- Prints, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sounds Like Art Contract, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Mail/Checks, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Town Hall Documents, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Returns from LRA Mailing, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Ad Orders, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Donations, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Ads, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Repertoire, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Ads, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Frankel, Erwin, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - 10th Anniversary Concert Notes, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Faxes, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Ads -- Calls/Faxes, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Guest Artists, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Price Lists/Sales, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - MC Letters/Press, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Scripts, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Ticket Order Payments, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Ticket Orders, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Program, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Ticket Forms, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Concert Roles, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Tenth Anniversary -- General, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Song, Struggle, and Solidarity, Mark Abendroth, 2020 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Commercial Recordings, 1995-2011 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)